Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman Papers, 1906-2000
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman papers
1906-2000
Cushman, Nancy Cox-McCormack, b. 1885
MS 40
12 boxes (4.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Sculptor, author, and traveler. This collection documents Cushman's professional life, artistic works, and her wide social network, particularly in Chicago in the 1910's and Europe in the 1920's. The subjects of Cushman's sculptures include Benito Mussolini, Ezra Pound, Italian architect Giacomo Boni, Spanish dictator Primo de Rivera, Mohandas K. Ghandi, Clarence Darrow, and Jane Addams. All are represented to some extent in the collection as are other notables such as Stephen Vincent Benét, Sarah Bernhardt, Lauro De Bosis, Alice Gerstenberg, Elizabeth Sparhawk Jones, Grace Hegger Lewis, Dorothy Shakespeare Pound, Eunice Tietjens, and Frank Lloyd Wright. Types of materials include correspondence, writings, photographs, clippings, biographical materials, artwork, and memorabilia.
Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman was an American sculptor, writer, artist, and socialite. Although she created some altar panels and abstracts, her work consisted mostly of portrait sculpture, primarily in bronze and terra cotta. Particularly productive between 1910 and 1953, her work included a broad range of well and lesser known people. These included Italian dictator Benito Mussolini, poet Ezra Pound, lawyer Clarence Darrow, social reformer Jane Addams, Italian architect Giacomo Boni, Spanish dictator Miguel Primo de Rivera, and Indian politician Mohandas K. Ghandi. Through her work and social contacts, Cushman cultivated a wide variety of notable friends and associates including the family of author Stephen Vincent Benet; social reformer Louis de Koven Bowen; Italian poet and anti-fascist Lauro De Bosis; Ezra and Dorothy Pound; artist Elizabeth Sparhawk Jones; writer and journalist Clara Laughlin; Grace Hegger Lewis, wife of Sinclair Lewis; opera singer Gladys Swarthout; and the family of architect Frank Lloyd Wright. Her work received little critical attention during her lifetime or since, but local newspapers covered her work and travels extensively.
Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman was born Nancy Mal Cox in Nashville, Tennessee, August 15, 1885, the second of three children of cousins Herschell McCullough Cox and Nancy Morgan Cox. She was descended from one of the first families to settle in Virginia in the early 1600s. Her mother studied music and painting and although it is not clear what her father's occupation was, in a letter to Alice Gerstenberg, Cushman writes " Like many southerners of inheritance my family was artistic." Her mother died of tuberculosis when Nancy was three. All three children contracted polio, and Nancy's elder sister and younger brother both died of the disease shortly before the death of their mother. The results if the illness affected Nancy's health for the rest of her life. Her father married Lillian Warren with whom he had one son, Henry Herschel Cox. In 1899, when Nancy was fourteen, her father was killed in a carriage accident on his way to view a newly acquired property. After a brief time in a boarding school in Arkansas, she and her stepmother moved to Nashville where Nancy was enrolled at Ward Seminary. At Ward she worked in pastels and watercolors under the direction of artist Willie Betty Newman. Nancy, cut off from her father's family and unhappy with her stepfamily and her "irrational stepmother," ran away and married Mark McCormack in 1903. She admitted that it was an "escape" marriage and they were soon divorced.
Left a "small income" by her father, Nancy enrolled at Washington University St. Louis School of Fine Arts in 1910 and then the Chicago Art Institute studying sculpture under Charles Mulligan. She worked in Chicago until 1920 during which time she sculpted over twenty-five pieces and wrote Peeps, The Really Truly Sunshine Fairy, a children's book published in 1918. It was during this time in Chicago that her life intersected with many well known people such as Clarence Darrow, Grace Hegger Lewis, Alice Gerstenberg, Eunice Tietjens, and Frank Lloyd Wright.
In 1921 Cushman traveled to Europe. While in France she became friends with Ezra Pound and his wife, Dorothy Shakespeare, whom she had met earlier in the States. In 1922 she opened a studio in Rome, and shortly thereafter she received a commission from the Italian American Society of Philadelphia to sculpt a bust of Benito Mussolini. It was during this period that she also did a bust of the Spanish dictator Primo de Rivera. Pieces produced during this time were exhibited in Paris at the Galleries Jacques Seligman, the Salon of 1923, and at the 1923-24 Exposition Biennale Internationale des Beaux Arts in Rome. They were also subsequently exhibited at Seligman, New York Gallery; the National Gallery in Washington D.C.; the Chicago Art Institute; and the California Palace of the Legion of Honor in San Francisco.
Cushman returned to the United States in 1924 settling in New York and Pennsylvania where she wrote her memoirs and a book, Pleasant Days in Spain. In 1931 she traveled to London to sculpt a portrait bust of Mohandas K. Gandhi. During the next eight years she sculpted a number of portrait busts and a bas-relief memorial medallion of Jane Addams. She continued to work on her memoirs and traveled throughout the United States speaking of her experiences.
In 1939 she married Charles Thomas Cushman, an employee of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York. They settled in Ithaca, New York, traveling extensively until his death in 1962. Her last work was her husband's tombstone. Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman died in Ithaca on February 17, 1967.
The Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman Papers consist of 4.25 linear feet of correspondence; writings, photographs, clippings, artwork, and memorabilia. They reflect her artistic work and related contacts as well as a wide social network, particularly in Chicago in the 1910s and Europe in the 1920s. The material is annotated by Cushman. The challenge for researchers using these papers is the fact that material on many of the people is spread throughout the collection. For example, information on Ezra Pound can be found in all four series as well as within the narratives of Cushman's memoirs and correspondence. This is also the case with photographs that are located in both SERIES III. and IV. because many were taken of Cushman at work with her models.
This collection is organized into four series:
I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS AND MEMORABILIA
II. CORRESPONDENCE
III. ARTWORK, SPEECHES, AND WRITINGS
IV. PHOTOGRAPHS
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The Papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman donated her papers to the Sophia Smith Collection beginning in 1948. She made additions over the years until her death in 1967. In 2001 Nancy Weyant donated letters from Cushman to Ethel Fairmont Beebe.
Search Terms
Artists, American--Biography--Sources; Chicago (Ill.)--History--20th century--Sources; Europe--Description and travel--Sources; Sculptors--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Sculpture, American--20th century; Women sculptors--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Women artists--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Addams, Jane, 1860-1935; Beard, Mary Ritter, 1876-1958--Correspondence; Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923; Bowen, Louise Hadduck de Koven, 1859-1953; Cushman, Nancy Cox-McCormack, b. 1885; De Bosis, Lauro, 1901-1931; Gandhi, Mahatma, 1869-1948; Gerstenberg, Alice; Mussolini, Benito, 1883-1945; Pound, Dorothy--Correspondence; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Primo de Rivera, Miguel, 1870-1930; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959
Additional Information
Related Material
There are also Cushman papers located at the Tennessee State Library and Archives. Her castings of Mussolini, Gandhi, and Lydia Rismondo are located at Cornell University's Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS AND MEMORABILIA
  - Genealogy, 1930-63, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cushman family, 1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cushman, Nancy Cox-McCormack
    [see also Friends and Associates-De Bosis, Lauro and Ghandi, Mohandes K.; SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE - Gerstensberg, Alice; SERIES III. ARTWORK, SPEECHES AND WRITINGS - Writings]
    - Diary portions, 1930-31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Memoir: "Two letters of Reminiscence Covering My Decade in Chicago, 1911-1920," 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Clippings and articles, 1919-67, 2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Horoscopes, numerology, and handwriting analysis, 1932-34, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia
      [see also Oversize materials]
      - Autograph book, 1922-57
        - Original (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Photocopy (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Programs and printed materials, 1915-56, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1914-62, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Friends and associates
    - Adams, George Matthew, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Addams, Jane, 1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Andersen, Stell, 1931-54, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Benet
      - Laura, 1939, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Stephen Vincent, 1943-62, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - William Rose, 1940-50, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous family, 1940, 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Benson, Allan L., 1916 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bernhardt, Sarah, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Boni, Giacomo, 1953, 1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
      [see also SERIES III. ARTWORK, SPEECHES AND WRITINGS-Writings]
    - Bowen, Louise de Koven, 1940-62 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Clark, Charles Upson, 1904-60, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Darrow, Clarence, 1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - De Bosis
      - Lauro
        - "An Italian Memoir: Incorporating the Story of Lauro DeBosis" by Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - "The Story of My Death," 1934-48 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Writings, 1927, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        - Articles, clippings, 1930-58, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Lillian Vernon, 1930, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - de la Gabbe, Juliette, 1928, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Doremus family, 1925, 1941, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Draper, Ruth, 1956-60 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Dromgoole, Will Allen, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - du Manoir, George H. 1934 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Edwards, India, 1944, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Evans, Rudolph, 1943-60, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
      [see also SERIES III. ARTWORK, SPEECHES, AND WRITINGS]
    - Favai, Gennaro, 1958, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Fekete, Zoltan, 1953-56, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gerstenberg, Alice, 1929-57, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
      [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE]
    - Ghandi, Mohandas K., 1931-60 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Haubiel, Charles, 1929, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Jones, Elizabeth Sparhawk, 1942-52, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Jonson, Raymond, 1947-58 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Jules-Bois, H.A., 1937-43 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Laycock, Craven, 1940, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Lester, Muriel, 1927-31, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Lewis, Grace Hegger, 1956, 1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - MacDowell, Marion and Edward, 1938-57, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - MacVeah, Eames, 1940-50, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Masters, Edgar Lee, 1917, 1944-50, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Monroe, Harriet, 1938, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Morrow, Libbie Lutrell, 1935, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Mussolini, Benito, 1924, 1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
      [see also SERIES III. ARTWORK, SPEECHES, AND WRITINGS - Writings]
    - Nobili, Grace Cleveland Porter, 1953-60 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Person, Edwin, 1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Pound
      - Ezra
        [see also SERIES II CORRESPONDENCE - Personal- Favari and SERIES III. ARTWORK, SPEECHES AND WRITINGS-Writings-Miscellaneous]
        - Biographical articles and clippings, 1923-60, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - "Some recollections of Ezra Pound" by Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Writings, 1912-17 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous printed material and notes by Ezra Pound, 1938-57, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Omar, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Rockefeller, Martha Baird, 1929-51 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Sciortino, Antonio, 1914-54, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Shenton, Edward, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Shipley family, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Tallmadge, Thomas E and Thomas H., 1924-40 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Tietjens, Eunice, 1917-44, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Walsh, William, 1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Women Poets, 1963-64 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1914-1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Personal
    - Adams, George M., 1911, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Stell, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - B, 1911-66, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Bailey, Vernon Howe, 1926, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Beebe, Ethel Snyder Fairmont, 1921, 1953-64 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Beard, Mary Ritter, 1940-52, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Benet, Laura, 1939-65, undated (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
    - Benson, Allan, 1919-23 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Bordeaux, Vahdah, 1931, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Bowen, Louise de Koven, 1925-53, undated (Box 5, Folder 11-16)
    - Brulen, Eva, 1927-52 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Burroughs, John, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - C, 1923-39 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Casanova, Grace Hegger
      [see Lewis]
    - Clark, Charles Upson, 1929-60 (Box 5, Folder 20-22)
    - Colosimo, Candida, 1956-59 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Colum, Padraic, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Cushman, Charles T., 1955 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - D, 1925, 1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Darrow, Clarence, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - de Bosis
      - Adolpho, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Lillian Vernon, circa 1923 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - De Boyden, Grace, 1928-50, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - de la Gabbe, Juliette, 1924-58, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Doremus, Arthur, 1937-51, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Dudley, Anne H. and Peter, 1916-19, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Du Manoir, George Henry, Viscount, 1922-25, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - E-F, 1914-56, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Earhart, Amelia, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Edwards, India, 1930-58 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Elliott, Laura Norwell, 1913-17 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Evans, Rudolph, 1941-55 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Fabiani, Augusta, 1927-31 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Fekete, Zolton and Ann, 1954-55, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Favari, Maria and Gennaro, 1956-58 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - French, Daniel Chester, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - G, 1920, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Gerstenberg, Alice, 1915-64, undated (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
    - Gould, Lawrence and Peg, 1931-57, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Grierson, Margaret Storrs, 1948-65 (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
    - H, 1914-33, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Hale, Irene, circa 1927-37 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Hamilton, Alice, 1935-40 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Haubiel, Charles, 1929-64 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Heistand, H.O., 1919, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Henderson, Jessie, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Holmes, John Haynes, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Hoskins, Ann and Stewart, 1933, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - J, 1936-47, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jones, Elizabeth Sparhawk, 1935-56, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Jones, Harriet Winchester, 1939-41, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Jonson, Vera, 1958-60 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Jordan, Thomas M., 1923-24 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Jules-Bois, H.A., 1941-42, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - K, 1930-31, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - L, 1931, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Laughlin, Clara, 1924-39 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Laughlin, May, 1941-50 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Lawson, David, 1942, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Laycock, Craven and Florence, 1928-52 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Lewis, Grace Hegger Casanova, 1938-56 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - M, 1918-57, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - McCulloch, Winifred, 1947-62, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - MacDowell, Marion, 1929-43 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - MacVeah, Eames, 1927-54, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Marsh, Daniel L. 1930 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Masters, Helen J., 1944, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Miller, Tam, 1963-65, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Monroe, Harriet, 1930, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Morrow, Libbie Luttrell, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Nobili, Grace, 1953-62, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Noice, Harold, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Obermer, Seymour, 1923-24, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Ohannessian, Griselda, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - P, 1917-29, n.d (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Pearson, Edwin, 1922-25, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Pound
      - Dorothy, 1921-58, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Ezra, 1936-57, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Isabel and Homer, 1924, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - R, 1941, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller, Martha Baird Allen, 1930-33, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Rose, Ray Clarke, 1924, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - S, 1912-62, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sciortino
      - Antonio, 1930-47 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - F. S., 1947-48 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Shenton, Barbara, 1940-58, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Shipley, Caleb and Helen, 1929-65 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Sperry, Amelia, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Stewart, John, 1916-20, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Stokes, Sarah, 1931-47 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Storms, Alice, 1927, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Swarthout, Gladys, 1919-43 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - T, 1923-65, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Tallmadge, Thomas, 1921-31, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Teller, Sidney, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Tietjens, Eunice, 1917-18 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Townley, Ephra, 1932-34 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Vacca, Virginia, 1958-66, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Walker, Dugald, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Wallace, Mildred, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Walsh, William, 1930, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Whitney, Janet, 1938, 1944, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1951, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Business, 1911-65, undated (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
- SERIES III. ARTWORK, SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
  - Drawings and sculpture
    - Addams, Jane, 1935-40, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Boni, Giacomo
      - Photographs, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Clippings and correspondence, 1923-53, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bowen, Louise de Koven, 1948-49 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Carmack, Edward Ward
      - Photographs, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Clippings and correspondence, 1911-62, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Clark, Charles Upson, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Cushman, Charles T., 1962 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - de Rivera, Primo, 1925-52 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Evans, Rudolph, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Ghandi, Mohandas K., 1931, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Gould, Lawrence McKinley, 1931-32, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Haubiel, Charles, 1929, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Mussolini, Benito, 1923-34 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Rismondo, Lidia, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1911-33, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Exhibit catalogs and advertisements, 1917-45 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Writings
    [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHCAL MATERIALS - De Bosis, Lauro; Ghandi, Mohandas K.; Pound, Ezra]
    - Boni, Giacomo, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Mussolini, Benito, 1923-29 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Peeps, The Really Truly Sunshine Fairy, 1918-19 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Pleasant Days In Spain, 1927-28 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous, 1917-60, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Radio broadcasts, interviews, and speeches, 1924-62 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Family
    - Cox family, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Cushman
      - Charles A. and Magnola, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Charles Thomas, 1949, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Nancy Cox-McCormack, 1910-61, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Friends and associates
    - Mussolini, Benito, 1923-24, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Pound family, 1923-37, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Shipley family, 1934-41, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd family and homes, 1915, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1914-49, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Oversize Materials
  - Caballero de la Orden del Merito Civil (Spanish medal), 1930 (Box 11)
  - Bas relief of Louise deKoven Bowen mounted on wood, 1948 (Box 11)
  - Portrait of Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman painted by Christian Abrahamson, 1914 (Box 12)
  - Unidentified phonograph record (Map-case Flat File)
  - Phi Gamma Mu certificate, 1928 (Map-case Flat File)
  - Photograph of Nancy Cox-McCormack Cushman with Rudolph Evans, 1936 (Map-case Flat File)
  - Music signed by Charles Haubiel, 1929 (Map-case Flat File)
  - Blueprint of fountain for Mrs. William Kenley, 1919 (Map-case Flat File)